Guide to the David Brion Davis Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Additional materials, 1949-2016; Accession 2017-M-0002
  - Research files
    - Fugitive slaves, general, assumptions regarding assimilation, Circa 1990s-circa 2010 (Box 40, Folder 21)
    - British view, fugitive slave issue, Circa 1990s-circa 2010 (Box 40, Folder 22)
    - Attitudes toward other minority groups, Circa 1990s-circa 2010 (Box 40, Folder 23)
    - Attitudes of immigrants, Circa 1990s-circa 2010 (Box 40, Folder 24)
    - American mission subverted, general, Circa 1990s-circa 2010 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - American mission subverted, slave power controls nation, Circa 1990s-circa 2010 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - American hypocrisy, Circa 1990s-circa 2010 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - New American revolution, Circa 1990s-circa 2010 (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Crusade (Anglo-Saxon) to Christianize, gradual progress through Christianity, Circa 1990s-circa 2010 (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - Fourth of July rhetoric, Circa 1990s-circa 2010 (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - Anglo-Saxon superiority, implied or stated, Circa 1990s-circa 2010 (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - Regeneration of world, working out of destiny, Circa 1990s-circa 2010 (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - Monarchy, democracy, aristocracy, and slavery, Circa 1990s-circa 2010 (Box 41, Folder 9)
    - Noble traditions and precedents (subverted), Circa 1990s-circa 2010 (Box 41, Folder 10)
    - "Framers" intentions, Circa 1990s-circa 2010 (Box 41, Folder 11)
    - How moral influence is best exerted (for social change), 1990s-2000s (Box 41, Folder 12)
    - French views of United States "mission" and new ideals, 1990s-2000s (Box 41, Folder 13)
    - Leonard Bacon, Hugh Davis, Circa 1998 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Pro-colonization, Bacon Family Papers, Circa 1990s-circa 2010 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Notes on Bacon Family Papers, etc., Circa 1990s-circa 2010 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Leonard Bacon, old chapter 3 material, Circa 2006-circa 2009 (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Leonard Bacon, new chapter 3 material, Circa 2006-circa 2009 (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - Biblical arguments, descent from Ham, curse of Canaan, Circa 2006-circa 2009 (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - Black view, colonization issue, Circa 1990s-circa 2010 (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - White abolitionist views of black abolitionists, Circa 1990s-circa 2010 (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - Black views of white abolitionists, Circa 1990s-circa 2010 (Box 42, Folder 9)
    - White (including abolitionist) view of free blacks, Circa 1990s-circa 2010 (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Black view, emancipation process proper approach for blacks, Circa 1990s-circa 2010 (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Black view, other minorities, Circa 1990s-circa 2010 (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - Biblical and religious arguments, role of churches, Circa 1990s-circa 2010 (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Race prejudice, Negrophobia, Circa 1990s-circa 2010 (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Biblical arguments refuted, Circa 1990s-circa 2010 (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Black Nationalism and emigration (chapter 2), Circa 1980s-circa 1990s (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - Free blacks compared to poor, Circa 1990s-circa 2010 (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - Notes on Cohen, Green, and Berlin, Circa 1990s-circa 2010 (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - Black view, race prejudice, negrophobia, Circa 1990s-circa 2010 (Box 43, Folder 10)
    - White view, black capability, Circa 1990s-circa 2010 (Box 43, Folder 11)
    - Amalgamation, Negrophobia, Circa 1990s-circa 2010 (Box 43, Folder 12)
    - Race prejudice, general, Circa 1990s-circa 2010 (Box 43, Folder 13)
    - White abolitionist views of blacks (general), Circa 1990s-circa 2010 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Notes on abolition and archival collections, Circa 1990s-circa 2010 (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Immigration, Circa 1990s-circa 2010 (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Bibliographie Project, 1980s (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Lucia Bergamasco Lenarda Bibliotheque Nationale notes, Circa 1980s-circa 2010 (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Notes on bibliography and archival collections, Circa 1980s-circa 2010 (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - Catholicism and slavery; slavery in the French colonies, Circa 1980s-circa 2010 (Box 44, Folder 7-8)
    - Slavery in Rome, Circa 1980s-circa 2010 (Box 44, Folder 9)
    - Notes and writings on abolition, Circa 1980s-circa 2010 (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Ira Berlin, Many Thousand Gone, Circa 1980s-circa 2010 (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - Curse of Ham and Canaan, Circa 1980s-circa 2010 (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - Russian slavery, Circa 1970s (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - Schism, What is a true abolitionist; true abolitionism defined, Circa 1980s-circa 2010 (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - Schism, General squabbling; new versus old organization, Circa 1980s-circa 2010 (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - Abolitionist views of each other, Circa 1980s-circa 2010 (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - Use of the press, powerful tool, Circa 1980s-circa 2010 (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - Use of the press, marketing abolitionism, Circa 1980s-circa 2010 (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - Illustrations and cartoons, Circa 1980s-circa 2010 (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - Tactics and techniques of opposition, Circa 1980s-circa 2010 (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - Mobs (tactics of opposition), Circa 1980s-circa 2010 (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - Conversion experience, Circa 1980s-circa 2010 (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - Evidence (truth and facts), Circa 1980s-circa 2010 (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - Abolition and political action, Circa 1980s-circa 2010 (Box 46, Folder 7)
    - Anti-Semitism, Circa 2004-circa 2006 (Box 46, Folder 8)
    - Philosophy, 2008–2016 (Box 46, Folder 9)
    - Antislavery, biography (including Sojourner Truth), Circa 1980s-circa 2010 (Box 46, Folder 10)
    - Antislavery, biography (including Sojourner Truth), student work, Circa 1980s-circa 2010 (Box 99, Folder 10)
    - French antislavery and emancipation, 1994 (Box 46, Folder 11)
    - Ezra, Shabbos Group, Circa 1980s-circa 2010 (Box 46, Folder 12)
    - George Washington and slavery, Circa 1980s-circa 2010 (Box 46, Folder 13)
    - Slavery and abolition, Gad Heuman, 2000 (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Civil War, as crucial test, 1980s-1990s (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - Abraham Lincoln and Civil War, 1994 (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - Chapter 5 on slavery and sectional conflict text for lecture use, Circa 1980s-circa 2010 (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - Post-war, Reconstruction and New South, 1994 (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - Reconstruction and post-emancipation South, Circa 1980s-circa 2010 (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - Revolutionary thought, social Darwinism, Circa 1980s-circa 2010 (Box 47, Folder 7-8)
    - Liberalism and socialism, Circa 1980s-circa 2010 (Box 47, Folder 9)
    - William James and Pragmatism, Circa 1980s-circa 2010 (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Mark Twain and American culture, Circa 1980s-circa 2010 (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - Reform, social gospel, progressive, Circa 1980s-circa 2010 (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - Progressive Era, Circa 1980s-circa 2010 (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - Boundary concept, notes, Circa 1970s-circa 2010 (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - Modernization, notes, Circa 1970s-circa 2010 (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - Republicanism, historical debate, Circa 1970s-circa 2010 (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - Enlightenment, Circa 1970s-circa 2010 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - Demographic and economic growth, Circa 1970s-circa 2010 (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - Social change, pre-1820, Circa 1970s-circa 2010 (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - Industrialization, manufacture, Circa 1970s-circa 2010 (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - Transportation revolution, Circa 1970s-circa 2010 (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - Commerce, urbanization, Circa 1970s-circa 2010 (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - Public land policy, sectionalism, tariffs, Circa 1970s-circa 2010 (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - Class, distribution, classless ideal, Circa 1970s-circa 2010 (Box 49, Folder 8)
    - Economic theories, laissez-faire and nationalism, Circa 1970s-circa 2010 (Box 49, Folder 9)
    - Material expansion and anxieties, gentility and domesticity, Circa 1970s-circa 2010 (Box 49, Folder 10)
    - Lecture, the Great Transformation, Circa 1970s-circa 2010 (Box 49, Folder 11)
    - Lecture, Jefferson Republicanism, Circa 1970s-circa 2010 (Box 49, Folder 12)
    - Jeffersonian heritage, split, Circa 1970s-circa 2010 (Box 49, Folder 13)
    - Thomas Paine, Circa 1970s-circa 2010 (Box 49, Folder 14)
    - Lecture, America in age of revolution, Circa 1970s-circa 2010 (Box 49, Folder 15)
    - Lecture, American's revolutionary heritage, Circa 1970s-circa 2010 (Box 49, Folder 16)
    - French Revolution, American response, Circa 1970s-circa 2010 (Box 49, Folder 17)
    - Indians and removal, Circa 1970s-circa 2010 (Box 49, Folder 18)
    - Indians and Indian policy, 1985 (Box 99, Folder 11)
    - Violence, Circa 1970s-circa 2010 (Box 49, Folder 19)
    - Jacksonian persuasion, Circa 1965-circa 2000s (Box 49, Folder 20)
    - Jacksonian persuasion, student work, Circa 1965-circa 2000s (Box 99, Folder 12)
    - Notes, correspondence, and clippings on slavery, uprisings, and politics, Circa 1980s-circa 2010 (Box 49, Folder 21)
    - Non-resistance, denies use of violence as method for obtaining rights, Circa 1980s-circa 2010 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Non-resistance and martyrdom, Elijah Parish Lovejoy murder, Circa 1980s-circa 2010 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Non-resistance, general views, Circa 1980s-circa 2010 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Harmony and conflict, use of war images, violence, and slavery as warfare, Circa 1980s-circa 2010 (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Harmony and conflict, harmony of interests, Circa 1980s-circa 2010 (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Dominion, capital over labor, Circa 1980s-circa 2010 (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - Dominion, forms of subordination, Circa 1980s-circa 2010 (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - Dominion, labor and compulsion, Circa 1980s-circa 2010 (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - Idea of freedom, liberty, slavery, Circa 1980s-circa 2010 (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - Post Civil War, concern for Freedmen, Circa 1980s-circa 2010 (Box 50, Folder 10)
    - Slave revolts, insurrections, response to use of violence, Circa 1980s-circa 2010 (Box 50, Folder 11)
    - Relationship, condition of free blacks versus slaves, Circa 1980s-circa 2010 (Box 50, Folder 12)
    - Concern for welfare of slave and Freedmen, Circa 1980s-circa 2010 (Box 50, Folder 13)
    - View of character of slaveholders, Circa 1980s-circa 2010 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Property and compensation, British views, Circa 1980s-circa 2010 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - Property and compensation versus ransom of Frederick Douglass and William Wells Brown, Circa 1980s-circa 2010 (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - Property and property in man, general and miscellaneous views, Circa 1980s-circa 2010 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Notes, Jamaica trip, and Stanley L. Engerman material, 1981 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Antislavery papers and manuscripts, British Empire, Circa 1980s-circa 2010 (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - Jamaica notes, 1981 (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - Notes on Cuban slavery, Circa 1980s-circa 2010 (Box 51, Folder 8)
    - Black view, advice for their welfare and improvement (free black), Circa 1980s-circa 2010 (Box 51, Folder 9)
    - Anti-colonization from 1831-1833, Circa 1980s-circa 2010 (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - Notes on Katherine Plymley papers, Circa 1980s-circa 2010 (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - Notes on Quakers, Puritanism, and religion, Circa 1960s-circa 2010 (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - Jonathan Prude and Timothy Shannon papers, Milan dress and deportment, Indians, and class, 1990s (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - Charles Verlinden Beginnings of Modern Civilization summary, Circa 1960s-circa 2010 (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - Book and essay summaries on Dahomey, Circa 1960s-circa 2010 (Box 52, Folder 6)
    - Interview with Brazilian newspaper, 2002 (Box 52, Folder 7)
    - Interview with New York Historical Society, 2004 (Box 52, Folder 8)
    - Unsorted research files, Circa 1960s-circa 2010 (Box 52, Folder 9-10)
    - Unsorted research files, Circa 1960s-circa 2010 (Box 53, Folder 1-7)
    - Unsorted research files, Circa 1960s-circa 2010 (Box 54, Folder 1-4)
    - Unsorted research files with unidentified writings, Circa 1960s-circa 2010 (Box 54, Folder 5-6)
    - Unsorted research files with unidentified writings, Circa 1960s-circa 2010 (Box 55, Folder 1-4)
    - Unsorted research files with unidentified writings, Circa 1960s-circa 2010 (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence
    - General
      - 1990–1991 (Box 57, Folder 1)
      - 1992–1993 (Box 57, Folder 2)
      - Letters, 1993-1995 (Box 57, Folder 3)
      - 1997 (Box 57, Folder 4)
      - 1999–2000 (Box 57, Folder 5)
      - 2000-2004 (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - American History Extract Program films, etc., 1974–1975 (Box 58, Folder 2)
    - India travel, 1967 (Box 58, Folder 3)
    - Phil Morgan issue, 2005 (Box 58, Folder 4)
    - Problem of Slavery in the Age of Revolution, 1967–1975 (Box 58, Folder 5-6)
    - Professional, 1999 (Box 58, Folder 7)
    - Slavery, 1979–2000 (Box 58, Folder 8)
    - Slavery, 1979–2000 (Box 59, Folder 1-5)
  - Program files
    Program files pertaining to Yale University include university records, which are restricted until 2048 as established by Yale Corporation regulations. http://web.library.yale.edu/mssa/collections/ research-use-of-yale-university-archives.
    - Conferences
      - Hartford conference, 2000 (Box 60, Folder 1)
      - South Carolina conference, 2000 (Box 60, Folder 2)
      - Emory conference, global slavery, 2003 May (Box 60, Folder 3)
      - Amistad conference, abolitionists, 1989 November (Box 60, Folder 4)
      - Northwest Ordinance conference, 1987 (Box 60, Folder 5)
      - Nottingham conference, 2000 (Box 60, Folder 6)
      - 2nd Circuit Judges conference, Amistad, 2008 June (Box 60, Folder 7)
      - Brown University Haiti conference, 2004 (Box 60, Folder 8)
      - 13th Amendment conference, 2009 (Box 60, Folder 9)
      - Haitian Revolution conference, 2002 (Box 60, Folder 10)
      - McGill University conference details, 2007 (Box 60, Folder 11)
      - Williamsburg conference, 1998 (Box 60, Folder 12)
      - History conference in honor of Davis, 2002 May (Box 60, Folder 13)
      - Rochester conference, Stanley L. Engerman, 2001 June (Box 60, Folder 14)
      - Houston conference, 2001 February (Box 60, Folder 15)
      - Yale and slavery conference papers, 2002 (Box 61, Folder 1)
      - Paris conference (cancelled), 2002 (Box 61, Folder 2)
      - Fugitives from Slavery conference, 2002–2003 (Box 61, Folder 3)
      - Venture Smith conference, 2006 (Box 61, Folder 4)
      - Conference, Walter Johnson, Circa 1960s-circa 2010 (Box 61, Folder 5)
      - From Chattel Bondage to State Servitude: Slavery in the 20th Century conference, 2003–2004 (Box 61, Folder 6)
      - 20th century slavery conference, 2007 (Box 61, Folder 7)
      - Biographies and introductions, Gilder Lehrman Center conference, 2002 (Box 61, Folder 8)
      - Hull conference, Wilberforce Institute for the study of Slavery and Emancipation (WISE), 2006 July (Box 61, Folder 9)
      - Harvard, DuBois slave trade group, 2006 (Box 61, Folder 10)
      - Davis commentary for slavery conferences, 1967–1969 (Box 61, Folder 11-12)
      - Haitian Revolution conferences, 1998–2004 (Box 61, Folder 13)
      - Organization of American Historians (OAH) session, 1999 April (Box 61, Folder 14)
      - Collective Degradation: Slavery and the Construction of Race conference, 2003 (Box 61, Folder 15)
      - Sisterhood and Slavery conference, 2001 October (Box 62, Folder 1)
      - Library of Congress Civil War conference, 2002 November (Box 62, Folder 2)
      - Unshackled Spaces, 2002–2003 (Box 62, Folder 3)
      - Milan Symposium, 1998 (Box 62, Folder 4)
      - Williamsburg slave trade conference, 1998 September (Box 62, Folder 5-6)
      - Tony Kronman Yale conference, 2001–2002 (Box 62, Folder 7)
      - Haitian Revolution conference, Charleston, 1998 (Box 62, Folder 8)
      - Haitian Revolution conference, Charleston, 1998 (Box 63, Folder 1)
      - Chicago slave trade conference, 1998 May (Box 63, Folder 2-3)
      - Gilder Lehrman conference, 2000 (Box 63, Folder 4)
      - Italian trip, Milan conference, Mantua, Venice, 1990 June (Box 63, Folder 5)
      - Bellagio conferences, 1984 (Box 63, Folder 6-7)
      - Princeton University Islamic conference, Circa 1960s-circa 2010 (Box 63, Folder 8)
      - Internal Slave Trade in the Americas conference, 1999 October (Box 63, Folder 9)
      - New Jersey Council for History Education (CHE) conference, Princeton University, 1997 (Box 63, Folder 10)
      - Underground Railroad, Freedom Project notes, Fugitive issue, and Cincinnati, 1997–1998 (Box 64, Folder 1)
      - Williamsburg talk, slave trade conference, 1998 (Box 64, Folder 2)
      - Milan conference notes and papers, 1996 (Box 64, Folder 3)
      - Unsorted conference files, 1968-1969 (Box 64, Folder 4)
    - Organizations
      - New York Seaport slavery exhibit, 1997–2001 (Box 65, Folder 1)
      - Bruce Catton Prize, 2004 (Box 65, Folder 2)
      - National Endowment for the Humanities official correspondence, 1975–1984 (Box 65, Folder 3)
      - Mellon Fellowship grant, 2007–2009 (Box 65, Folder 4)
      - National Endowment for the Humanities report, 1979–1981 (Box 65, Folder 5)
      - National Endowment for the Humanities (44658) project description and initial budget, 1981 (Box 65, Folder 6)
      - Kidger Award, 2004 (Box 65, Folder 7)
      - Book prizes, 2006–2007 (Box 65, Folder 8)
      - Phi Beta Kappa Emerson Award, 2007 (Box 65, Folder 9)
      - Black Antislavery Writings Project Detroit, 2002 (Box 65, Folder 10)
      - Cincinnati Freedom Center, 2005–2006 (Box 65, Folder 11)
      - Yale University
        - Gilder Lehrman Center
          University records are restricted until 2048 as established by Yale Corporation regulations. http://web.library.yale.edu/mssa/collections/research-use-of-yale-university-archives.
          - Activities and outreach, 2002–2004 (Box 66, Folder 1)
          - Susan Saidenberg, 1992–1997 (Box 66, Folder 2)
          - Benjamin Franklin Papers, 2012 (Box 66, Folder 3)
          - Gilder Lehrman Center update, 2000 (Box 66, Folder 4)
          - Correspondence, 1992–2000 (Box 66, Folder 5)
          - Jamaica art conference, 2007 (Box 66, Folder 6)
          - Slavery and abolition, 1996–1998 (Box 66, Folder 7)
          - Gilder Lehrman Institute board, 1994–2003 (Box 66, Folder 8-9)
          - Abolitionism in America, Summer 2011 (Box 66, Folder 10)
          - General, 2013 (Box 66, Folder 11-12)
          - Gilder Lehrman Institute advisory board, 2006 (Box 66, Folder 13)
          - Publications, 1998–2002 (Box 66, Folder 14)
          - Volume introductions, 2002–2003 (Box 67, Folder 1)
          - Personnel and curricula vitae, 1998–2004 (Box 67, Folder 2)
          - Budget reports, 1998–2004 (Box 67, Folder 3)
          - Hebe Maria Mattos, 2002–2003 (Box 67, Folder 4)
          - Advisory committee, 1998–2004 (Box 67, Folder 5)
          - Planning, 1998–2002 (Box 67, Folder 6)
          - Names and priorities, 1998–2004 (Box 67, Folder 7)
          - Joe Miller bibliography project, 2003 (Box 67, Folder 8)
          - Frederick Douglass Book Prize, 1998–2003 (Box 67, Folder 9)
          - Frederick Douglass Book Prize, 1998–2003 (Box 68, Folder 1-4)
          - Slavery and abolition, 1998–2002 (Box 68, Folder 5-6)
          - Report documents and anthology, 1992–1997 (Box 68, Folder 7)
          - Gilder Lehrman Fellow leave of absence, 1996–1997 (Box 68, Folder 8)
          - Jim Basker, 2001–2003 (Box 68, Folder 9)
          - Seminar evaluations, 1999 (Box 68, Folder 10)
          - Meetings, 2000–2002 (Box 68, Folder 11)
        - Yale University files
          Contains personnel records, which are restricted until 2073 as established by Yale Corporation regulations. http://web.library.yale.edu/mssa/collections/research-use-of-yale-university-archives.
          - Professional activities, 1980–2005 (Box 69, Folder 1-5)
          - Professional activities, 2006 (Box 70, Folder 1)
          - Researchers, 2001 (Box 70, Folder 2)
          - Postdoctoral assistance, 2007–2008 (Box 70, Folder 3)
          - Retirement, 1999–2004 (Box 70, Folder 4)
          - Graduate Employees and Students Organization, 1995–2001 (Box 70, Folder 5-6)
          - Student records, 1995–2002 (Box 70, Folder 7)
  - Personal papers
    - David Brion Davis tributes, 2010–2012 (Box 71, Folder 1)
    - Howard University 1994 visit, 1993–1997 (Box 71, Folder 2)
    - Davis PhD thesis, 1956 (Box 71, Folder 3-4)
    - Harvard schoolwork, 1952–1953 (Box 71, Folder 5)
    - Dartmouth schoolwork, 1949–1950 (Box 71, Folder 6-7)
    - Dartmouth essays, 1965–1966 (Box 72, Folder 1)
    - Dartmouth course materials and teaching, 1953–1954 (Box 72, Folder 2)
    - Thoughts, reflections, family correspondence, and diary, 1977–2000 (Box 72, Folder 3)
    - Vita, Who's Who in America, and biographical material, 2005–2009 (Box 72, Folder 4)
    - Forbes and Stewart remarks on Davis retirement, 2004 June (Box 72, Folder 5)
    - Work schedule and records, 1986–1993 (Box 72, Folder 6)
    - Davis Wikipedia entry, 2009 (Box 72, Folder 7)